咖啡来了
Made you a coffee.
这么说昨晚不是梦
So it wasn't a dream.
不是
No.
你绝对  没有做梦
You definitely... weren't dreaming.
你是对的
Uh, you were right.
我完全没想到
I had no idea.
那你喜欢吗
So you liked it?
-喜欢  -哪怕是那部分我们...
- Yeah. - Even the part where I--
尤其是那部分  我好喜欢
Especially that part. I loved that.
很好  我也喜欢
Good. Me too.
那么
So...
你是  来真的对吗
You're on-- on board with this, right?
这不是什么
It's not some
"我辞职了  我差点挂掉"
"Oh, I-I quit my job, I almost died,
危机诱发的冲动激情什么的
I'm in crisis" thing?
不  我不这么想
Uh, no. Not for me.
那就好  我也没这么想
Okay. Me neither.
好的
Okay.
很好
Good.
但我...
But I, uh...
我的确辞职了
I did just quit my job.
我今天不用上班
And I do have the day off.
我也是
I-I do... too.
是嘛
Oh, really?
是的
Yes.
那么你
So what would you, um...
今天想做点什么
Like to do today?
不知道  我们可以看看书
Um, I don't know. We could read.
看看电视
We could watch tv.
对  吃点东西
Yeah. We could get something to eat.
可以这样
We could do that, yeah.
理查德  我回来了
Richard, I'm home!
我的天
Oh, my god.
天呐
Oh, god.
你不是说她去了汉普顿吗
You said she was at the Hamptons.
她的确去了汉普顿
She was in the Hamptons.
她不应该出现在家里的
She's not supposed to be here.
儿子  我们得谈谈
Darling, we need to talk.
躲起来
Hide.
-什么  -躲起来
- What? - Hide.
-你说真的吗  -躲到衣橱里
- Are you serious? - Get in the closet.
不  我才不躲到衣橱里呢
No, I'm not going in the closet.
快躲到衣橱里
Get in the closet!
出什么事了
What's going on?
我只是
I'm just...
在铺床
making the bed.
你怎么回来了
What are you doing here?
我想和你谈谈
Well, I wanted to talk to you about
你宝贝女儿的许多优秀品质
your daughter's many fine qualities...
一定得现在谈吗
Do we have to do this now?
顺便提醒你
And to remind you
我们家阿丽克西斯是个模范生
that our Alexis is a paragon of--
她优雅机智  成熟
Of grace and good sense and maturity,
虽然这些优秀品质是遗传谁的  我不知道
although where she got those qualities, I do not know.
是啊
Right.
如果我穿上衣服的话
I would just be so much more comfortable
谈论这个话题会更自在些
having this conversation with my clothes on.
好的
Well, yes.
我们在厨房等你
We'll meet you in the kitchen.
"我们"  阿丽克西斯也回来了吗
"We"? Alexis is here, too?
喝点茶怎么样
How about some tea?
茶可以解解酒
Tea can be very soothing.
不想喝
Oh, no. No tea.
不喝茶
No tea.
阿丽克西斯  你是宿醉了吗
Alexis, are you hungover?
毕业晚会上大家都玩疯了
Well, the graduation festivities got a tad out of hand,
阿丽克西斯给我打了电话
and Alexis called me from the party.
我开车到城里接的她
I drove into town, I picked her up.
拜托不要生气  亲爱的
So please don't get angry, darling.
你怎么不打给我
Well, why didn't you call me?
我打了  你没接
I tried. You didn't pick up.
对哦
Right.
是我的错
And... that's on me.
是我不好
That's my bad.
阿丽克西斯  作为你的父亲
Well, Alexis, as your father,
我得说  我...
I have to say, that I am...
对你非常失望  但奇怪的是  也很自豪
deeply disappointed in you, and yet, oddly proud.
我脑袋快炸了
Oh, my head is pounding.
亲爱的  我去给你拿阿司匹林
Oh, honey, I'll get you a couple of aspirin.
不行
Oh, no!
不能吃阿司匹林
No aspirin.
什么意思  为什么不行
What do you mean? Why not?
这是她第一次宿醉
It's her first hangover.
这是座里程碑  是必经之路
I mean, this is a milestone. It's a right of passage.
你不想认真地体验一下这种感觉
Don't you want to experience this in its--
毫无缓解地  真实贴切地  而不靠那些
in its fullness, un-- untrammeled by the--the relief
非处方止痛药减轻症状吗
of over-the counter pain relievers?
不想
No.
不吗  好吧  去吃阿司匹林吧宝贝  抱歉
No. Okay. Aspirin it is, sweetheart. I'm sorry.
那么  枪击贝克特的嫌犯有何进展
So... Any progress on Beckett's shooter?
我们搜查了他租的车
We searched his rental car.
还是不知道他当时的目的地
We still have no idea where he was going
以及他的真名
or even what his real name was.
但我们发现了他从蒙哥马利警监那里偷走的物品
But we did find out what he stole from Captain Montgomery's house.
蒙哥马利的结婚相册
The Montgomerys' wedding album?
马多克斯要这个做什么
Why did Maddox want this?
我的猜测是  他想要这张失踪的相片
I'm guessing he wanted this missing photograph.
有可能相片中的人就是他的追踪目标
It's possible he was after whoever was in it.
你查到是谁了吗
Have you been able to track it down?
我让伊芙琳·蒙哥马利把底片带来了
Well, I've got Evelyn Montgomery bringing the negatives in.
但事实是  现在队里就我一个人
But truth is, I'm a one-man band here.
人手紧缺啊
I could use a few more investigators.
你可以找副总统要人
Well, you can take it up with the vice president.
我已经派了一半的人去给他做安保
I've already lost half my people to his security detail...
另一半又要浪费在交通管制上了
and about to lose the rest to traffic control.
因此现在  你只能独挑大梁了
So for right now, you're on your own.
你这是在白白找罪受  史密斯先生
You're putting yourself through this for nothing, Mr. Smith.
我们都知道结局会如何
We both know how it will end.
别逼我用更毒辣的手段逼供你
Don't make me take this to the next level.
告诉我文件在哪
Tell me where the file is.
去死吧
Go to hell.
你过来是为让我藏在衣柜里那事道歉的吗
So you here to apologize for hiding me in your closet?
听我解释
Look, let me explain.
我听到她的声音时
When I heard her voice,
完全是触发了本能反应
I reacted by instinct.
是啊  就像纯情高中生般的本能反应
Yeah, like the instinct of a sophomore in high school.
没错
Right.
不  听着
No. Look, I--
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是羞于让人家看见你和我在一起
You're embarrassed about being seen with me.
不是那么回事
Now that is not true.
听着  我  这个  我
Look, I--this--I--
好吧  我还在适应我们的关系
Okay... this is all just still very new to me,
说我自私也好
and call me selfish,
我只是希望我们的关系
but I want to keep what we have together
暂时处于保密阶段
to ourselves a bit longer.
反正  那算不上你的最佳表现时刻哈
Still, it wasn't your finest hour.
不算
No.
或许我可以
But maybe I could...
做点事情补偿你一下
make it up to you... somehow.
既然你妈妈这次不会再搞突然袭击了
I suppose since we know that your mom's not gonna be barging in,
我们可以来第二轮
we could go for round two.
严格说来  应该是第四轮了
Well, technically, it would be round four, but--
她在跟踪我们  她知道了
She's stalking us. She knows.
是谁
Who is it?
贝克特  我是莱恩
Beckett, it's Ryan.
藏起来
Hide.
快点  到那边衣柜里去
Quick. In the closet over there.
是啊  我才不去
Yeah, I'm not getting in there.
为什么  我都躲进你的衣柜  你怎么就不行
Why? I hid in your closet. Why can't you hide in mine?
-我为什么要躲  -因为
- Why should I? - Because--
-贝克特  你没事吧  -没事
- Beckett, is everything okay? - Fine.
我也没准备好让大家都知道
Okay, maybe I'm not ready for anyone to know yet...
快去
Right now.
拜托  他怎么会知道
Come on. How's he gonna know?
你在我家  就像我在你家一样
You're here, just like I was there.
是的  是的  但不同的是
Yes, yes, the difference being,
我现在是穿着裤子的
I have my pants on.
或者说  你羞于让别人见到我们在一起
Or... or are you embarrassed to be seen with me?
好的
Okay. Fine.
表现得正常一点
Just act normal...
虽然那对你来说不大可能
if that's even possible for you.
那就是我的风格
It's me.
嘿  卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我正好经过
Well, I was just walking by
附近  街区
The neighbor... hood.
我家离这里20...
I only live 20...
你来干什么
Uh, what are you doing here?
我要和你们谈谈案子的事
I need to talk to you about the case.
莱恩
Uh, Ryan.
不  莱恩
Uh, no, Ryan.
我辞职了  我不干了
I've resigned. I'm done.
听着
Look...
我希望这不是因为盖茨
I hope this isn't because of Gates
或是我的所为
or... because of what I did.
不不  听着  我理解的
No. No, look, I get it.
你当时只是想保护我们
You were just trying to keep us safe.
我现在也是
I still am.
那个把你扔下屋顶的人
And this guy that threw you off the roof,
他仍逍遥法外
He's still out there.
莱恩
Ryan--
我知道这个案子对你造成的种种伤害
I know what this case has done to you.
我不是让你重新跳回火坑
I'm not asking you to jump back in.
我只想让你看看一些东西  仅此而已
I just want to show you something. That's all.
我们找到了马多克斯从婚礼相册拿走的照片副本
We found a copy of the photo Maddox took From the wedding album.
你对以前和罗伊一起工作的人都很熟悉
You're familiar with the guys that Roy ran with back in the day.
他是其中的一员吗
Is he one of them?
我之前从没见过他
I've never seen him before.
我见过
I have.
他就是我和你说过的那个保证你安全的人
This is the man I told you about, the one who's been keeping you safe.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
他现在变老了  但绝对是他
He's older now, but it's definitely him.
我们  现在到底在说什么
What--what are we talking about here?
不管蒙哥马利给了他什么信息
Whatever information Montgomery gave to him,
他一直用它来保护你
He's been using it to protect you.
但现在他们派了
But now they've sent...
马多克斯追查他  并把信息抢回来
Maddox to hunt him down and get it back.
如果我们不抢在马多克斯之前找到他
If we don't get to him before Maddox does,
你就永远别想安全了
you'll never be safe again.
马多克斯要找的这个人
This guy who Maddox is looking for,
就是问题的关键
he's the key.
找到他  就能找到蒙哥马利的文件
We find him, we find Montgomery's file.
也就能找到这一切的幕后黑手
Which could lead to who's behind this whole thing,
包括你妈妈的被害案
including your mother's murder.
你们交谈过那么多次
And all the times you talked,
他从没透露过自己的名字吗  假名也算啊
He never gave you a name, even a fake one?
-没  -那他工作的地方呢
- No. - Or where he worked?
-没  -家庭住址
- No. - Where he lived?
没有  这类信息从来没有
No, nothing like that.
他打过我手机
He, um, he called my cell phone.
就在两天之前
Uh, two nights ago. Uh, uh...
但号码是屏蔽的
But from a blocked number.
我去查你的通话记录
I'll run your phone records,
看看我能不能查到他的号码
See if I can trace the number that he called from.
一切该就此结束了才对
This was supposed to be over.
我不能再陷进去了  现在不能
I can't go back again. Not now.
但现在我们别无选择
Well, now we don't have a choice.
如果马多克斯比我们先找到他
If Maddox gets to him before we do--
但是我不知道怎么做
But I don't know how to do this.
我现在连警察都不是了
I'm not even a cop anymore.
我来告诉你我们怎么做
I'll tell you exactly what we do.
我们查出他是谁
We figure out who this is.
我们以前也做过的  线索甚至更少
We've done it before, and with less to go on.
等我们做到了  我们让这一切都结束
And when we do, we lay all of this to rest,
然后我们再回到以前
And we go back to where we were.
你很擅长这个的
This is what you're great at.
不过我在这方面也不差
And I'm not so bad myself.
所以
So...
我们有什么线索
What do we know?
我们知道这个人约60多岁  长住纽约
We know this guy is about 60, he's a long-time new yorker,
是蒙哥马利的朋友
Uh, friends with Montgomery,
所以他可能与执法机构有联系
So he may have connections to law enforcement.
他
He, um...
他看起来身份显赫
He seems prominent,
富有
wealthy.
对
That's right.
而且他在拍照的时候  就已经权财兼备了
And he has been that way ever since this photo was taken.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
看他的手表
Look at his wrist.
那是百达翡丽3800
That's a Nautilus 3800.
1981年问世的时候就卖一万美元
It was 10 grand when it came out in 1981.
而且
And...
蒙哥马利正是在那年结婚的  1981年五月
That's the year Montgomery was married--May of 1981.
这样的手表在五个月里
How many of these watches
能卖出去多少呢
could possibly have been sold in five months?
哈维尔  你吩咐的事我不能做
Javi, I can't do what you're asking.
我可是曾为你挨过一枪  卡斯
I took a bullet for you, Cass.
你忘了吗
You forget that?
我不能在没有授权的情况下
I can't tap into the D.O.D. database
进入国防部的数据库
without authorization.
我会失去一切的  兄弟
I'll lose everything, man.
前提是你被发现
Only if you get caught.
但你不会被发现的
And you won't.
我用现金从一个资产清算人那里买来的
I bought this from a liquidator, cash.
我们一完成  我就格掉硬盘
Soon as we're done, I'll wipe the drive,
扔掉盒子  永远反查不到你身上
ditch the box. It'll never come back to you.
他以前是军人
He's former army.
特种部队  三角洲特种队  我也不知道
Special forces, Delta-- I don't know.
他射伤了我的朋友  差点杀死了她
This guy shot a friend of mine, almost killed her.
如果不阻止他  他是不会就此罢手的
He's gonna keep coming unless he's stopped.
我必须知道他的身份
I need to I.D. Him.
你得帮我
You need to help me.
好的  嗯  谢谢
Okay. Yes. Thank you.
好吧  手表公司说1981年一月到五月期间
All right, the watch company says that 17 of the 3800s...
在纽约卖掉17块3800S手表
were sold in New York in 1981 between January and May.
他们有没有把这17个人的名字告诉你
And did they give you names of any of these clients?
没有  不过17块表里面
No, but 9 of the 17 watches
有9块是作为礼物送给一家隶属
were given as gifts to a legal team
PPC法律事务所的律师团
at the law firm of P.P.C.
因为他们刚赢了一起针对烟草巨头的民事诉讼
after they won a civil suit against big tobacco.
这样的民事诉讼肯定会有大量媒体报道
Winning a tobacco lawsuit would get a lot of publicity.
运气好的话我们甚至能
With any luck, we'll I.D.
在莱恩追查电话之前找到此人
this guy before ryan even traces that call.
什么叫你没法查到这个电话
What do you mean you can't trace the call?
为什么不行
Why the hell not?
我这边时间很紧
Look, I'm on the clock here.
必须马上知道是谁打的电话
I need to know who made that call. Now.
可  好吧  好吧  让霍本警官来接
But--yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Just put officer Hoben on.
我平时都是找他
He's the guy I usually deal with over there.
这就是打赢官司的PPC律师团
Okay, so this is the P.P.C. Legal team that won the suit,
可是  他不在这上面
but I...Don't see him.
那是个9人团队
It was a 9-man team.
照片上只有8个  没来的那个应该就是他
There's only eight here. He must be the missing lawyer.
也有可能他根本就不是律师
Or he's not a lawyer at all.
或者他确实是律师  不过他...
Or he is a lawyer, but he operates...
是在背后出力的那种
behind the scenes.
他可能是
He would be, um,
"高级顾问"  就像迈克尔·克雷顿一样
"Of counsel," like Michael Clayton.
卡塞尔  这张照片都是30年前的了
Castle, this photo is 30 years old.
没人知道这人是否还在这家公司
We have no idea if this guy still works at that law firm
甚至可能他当年也不是这家公司的
or if he ever worked there at all.
-贝克特  -坏消息
- Beckett. - Bad news.
那家伙给卡塞尔打电话用的是一次性手机
The number the guy called Castle from came from a burner phone,
现在已经停用了
and it's out of service.
不管那人是谁  他在刻意隐藏行踪
Whoever this guy is, he covered his tracks.
我们已经通缉了马多克斯
Look, we put out alerts for Maddox.
照片已经发到全州去了
We circulated his photo all over the state.
总会有人看见他的
Someone will spot him.
可一直等也不是个办法
Well, we can't wait for that.
你有没有查到什么
Did you get anything?
倒是有一点线索  但能查到的希望不大
Well, there is one thing, but it's a long shot.
那家伙用的不是普通手机  而是网络电话
The guy used voice-over-internet instead of normal cell service,
他在一个信号很差的地方打了个电话
but he made a call in a bad signal area
是连接无线网之后拨打的
that got routed through a wireless network.
如果真是通过网络  那一定就有IP地址
Well, if it's a network, it'll have an I.P. Address.
没错  我们追查了IP
Yeah, and we traced it.
那个电话甚至都不是在纽约打的
Um, uh, it's not even in New York.
-那是在哪儿  -这通电话
- Then where is it? - The call
用的无线网络注册地在麦哲伦游艇俱乐部
went through a wireless network that's registered
位于康涅狄格州的韦斯特波特市
to the Magellan Yacht Club in Westport, Connecticut.
谢了  莱恩
Thanks, Ryan.
他应该是俱乐部的会员
He must be a member of this club.
也许这个网站上会有他的照片
Maybe there's a picture of him somewhere Posted on the site?
卡塞尔
Castle.
看
Look.
高级顾问律师名单上有这个名字
On the "Of counsel" Attorney list.
再看董事会一栏
Now look at the board of directors.
迈克尔·史密斯  就是他
Michael Smith. That's him.
看来被马多克斯抢先一步
Looks like Maddox found him first.
文件
The file.
卡塞尔
Castle.
他还活着
He's still alive.
抱歉  听得见我说话吗
Excuse me, can you hear me?
先生  请你退后
Sir, I'm asking you to step away.
文件
The file...
不安全
It's not safe.
86...
86  什么意思  什么86
86? What does that mean? 86...
-我不知道你在说什么  -86 马...
- I don't know what that means. - 86 M--
先生  我们必须送他到急诊室
Sir, we need to get him to the E.R..
我不懂  等等
I don't understand. Wait.
-不行  得马上走  -那是什么意思
- No, we have to get him to the E.R.. - What does that mean?
史密斯要能活下来
If Smith makes it,
恐怕莱恩要派人时刻保护他了
Ryan's gonna put him under police guard,
免得马多克斯又折回来
Make sure that Maddox doesn't come back
把他干掉
and finish off the job.
史密斯刚给了我一条线索  他说"86"
Smith just gave me a message. He said "86."
肯定跟文件有关
It has to be a clue to where the file is.
我们知道文件在哪啊  就在火堆里
We know where the file is. It's right there.
烧得只剩灰烬了
It's burnt to a crisp.
不  史密斯很聪明
No, Smith is too smart
不可能只留一份放在公寓里
to only keep one copy in--in his apartment.
他非常谨慎小心的  他...
He's too careful for that. He's...
那是个代码
It's a code.
答案一定就在这里什么地方
The answer's here somewhere.
我们得走了
We need to go.
答案一定就在这儿
Well, the answer's got to be here.
肯定在
It's somewhere here.
卡塞尔  这里没什么好找的了
Castle, there's nothing left to find.
86这个数字太宽泛
86 could mean anything.
你这完全就是在孤注一掷
You're just grasping at straws.
没错  我就是孤注一掷
Yes, I'm grasping at straws,
如果文件不见了
Because if that file is gone,
说明他们就要冲你来了
that means they're coming after you,
到时我就没办法保护你
And there's absolutely nothing I can do.
所以  没错  如果剩最后一根救命稻草
So, yes, if there is a straw, I'm--
我会紧抓着不放
I'm grasping.
卡塞尔  我们甚至不该出现在这里
Castle, we're not even supposed to be here.
当警察到这里时
When uniforms come here,
他们会以私闯民宅罪逮捕我们的
they're gonna arrest us for breaking and entering.
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time.
史密斯在下曼哈顿区有处房产
Smith owns property in Lower Manhattan.
这个  马克威尔街86号
This one-- 86 Markwell street.
史密斯说的就是这个
That's what Smith said.
他说"86"  还有"马"音
He said "86" and then "Ma-ma-ma,"
像是一个M打头的单词
Like something started with "M."
文件就在这栋楼里
This building, this is where the file is.
好吧
All right, so...
这栋楼才十层
The building is ten stories.
找一份文件不会有多难  对吧
How hard can it be to find a file, right?
他肯定把它藏在
He would've hid it in a place
不会被拆迁人员发现的地方
that was safe from the demolition crew.
是的  也就是说史密斯先生
Yes, which suggests that Mr. Smith
不仅拥有这栋楼
not only owns this building,
还对楼的结构了如指掌
but he knows it inside and out.
谢了
Thanks.
谢什么  我们还没找到呢
For what? We haven't found it yet.
我知道  如果不是因为你
Just I-I-I know I never would've gotten this far
不可能查到这一步
if it wasn't for you.
你和我  我们会圆满解决这事的
Hey, we're gonna get this done, you and me.
我们先排除所有的内墙
And we're gonna start by ruling out all the interior walls.
史密斯不会冒险藏在那儿的
Smith wouldn't risk hiding it there
那些石膏板都会被拆掉的
with all the sheetrock getting torn down.
天花板也不可能
Ceilings are no good either.
卡塞尔
Castle.
迈克尔·史密斯  523室
Michael Smith. 523.
他不仅是整栋楼的所有者
He didn't just own the building.
他在五楼还有个办公室
He had an office on the fifth floor.
还真是有用的信息
Well, that's some helpful information.
转过身去  手背后面
Turn around. Hands behind your back.
你就是不懂何时该放弃  是吧
You just don't know when to quit, do you?
所以你说服史密斯告诉你文件所在
So you convinced Smith to tell you where the file was.
他说文件被安全地藏在某层楼里
He told me it was hidden in a floor safe,
但却不肯透露具体地址
but he didn't tell me exactly where.
幸运的是  你们替我想出来了
Good thing you guys cleared that up.
你没杀他是因为你怕找不到文件
You didn't kill him in case you couldn't find the file.
等我找到之后  我就能来算你这笔账了
And once I do, I'm finally gonna settle our account.
一会儿见
See you soon.
好吧  我们有一两分钟的时间离开这里
Okay, we've got a minute, maybe two to get the hell out of here.
卡塞尔  你的扣条有多紧
Castle, how tight are your zip ties?
-你的手能动吗  -不  只能一点点
- Can you move your hands at all? - No, just barely.
你的口袋里有什么锋利的东西吗
Do you have anything sharp in your pocket...
-没有  -比如小刀
- Uh, no. - Like a knife,
-指甲钳  -没有  谁会带指甲钳啊
- nail clippers? - No. Who carries nail clippers?
你有钥匙吗
Do you have keys?
没有  我家门是遥控的
No, it's a fob. It's a remote.
这  这里有个干壁钉  好极了
There's--there's--there's a-a drywall screw. Perfect.
那  那有什么用
That's-- that's not gonna help.
恕我不能赞同
Ah, I beg to differ.
我所要做的是  拿着扣条
All I have to do is grab the zip tie
用钉子把它锯断
and... saw through.
我连一点痕迹都没磨出来
I am barely making a dent in this thing.
卡塞尔  我听见脚步声了  他回来了
Castle, I hear footsteps. He's coming.
快点
Hurry.
如果现在被他杀了  我会觉得亏大了
If we got murdered right now, I'd feel so ripped off.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
至少
At least...
至少我们共度了昨晚
At least we had last night.
我们在4年前就该这么做了
We should've done that four years ago.
4年前该做什么
Done what four years ago?
马多克斯的真名叫塞德里克·马科斯
Maddox's real name is Cedric Marks.
他服完兵役之后
Once he finished his tour,
在阿兰特斯方案公司找了份工作
he got a job at a place called Arantus Solutions,
是一种雇佣兵军事承包商
a kind of black-ops military contractor.
你是怎么找到这里来的
How'd all that lead you here?
得到他的名字后  我就派人留意他的车
Well, once I got his name, I put a bolo out on his car.
一名警察在这栋楼外面发现了
A uniform spotted it outside this building.
等我过来核实时  就发现了你的车
When I came to check on it, that's when I saw your car.
等等  埃斯波西托
Wait, wait, Espo.
523在转角处  你还有枪吗
523 is around the corner. You got an extra piece?
有
Yeah.
好极了  那我呢
Nice. What about for me?
你难道要我带两把备用的枪吗
Oh, you mean an extra extra piece?
不许动
Don't move.
喘气都不行
Don't even breathe.
敢拿枪  我就一枪崩了你
Reach for it, and I'll blow your head off.
好吧  警探  你是老大
Okay, detective. You're in charge.
慢慢弯腰  把文件给我
Now slowly reach down and hand me the file.
他死了
He's gone.
多谢警告  史密斯
Thanks for the warning, Smith.
他知道马多克斯会先到这里
He knew that Maddox would show up here first.
这是什...
What the...
是文件
The file.
听听我的理解对不对
So let me see if I understand.
无巧不成书  你们三个
As luck would have it, you three
都在这个街区里散步
were in the neighborhood taking a walk?
很多人都认为  散步是最好的锻炼方式
Well, many people consider that the best form of exercise.
那是低冲击运动  而且...
It's low impact, it has--
然后你们听见爆炸声
Then you heard an explosion,
作为热心的普通市民
and as concerned private citizens,
你们就冲进来查看情况
You rushed inside to check it out?
对  是这样的
Yeah. That's right.
你记得的情况也是这样的吗
Is that how you remember it?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
盖茨警监  我能以个人担保
Captain Gates, I can personally vouch for that--
我没兴趣  卡塞尔先生
I am not interested, Mr. Castle,
你可是编故事的高手
as you specialize in fiction.
我就姑且认为你们是碰巧在附近
Let's say you happened to be in the area.
但你们又怎么解释马多克斯
How do you explain the fact that Maddox,
也就是我们正搜捕的那个凶手
the killer we're searching for
也是去年开枪杀你的人
and the man who shot you last year,
死在这儿了
is the one lying there dead?
恶有恶报
Bad karma.
莱恩警探
Detective Ryan.
你知道关于此事的什么情况吗
Do you know anything about this?
我只知道保险柜被动了手脚
Just that it appears the safe was rigged
马多克斯一打开就爆炸了
to blow when Maddox opened it.
那保险柜里有什么
And what was in that safe?
很难说
Hard to say.
好像是些文件
Papers of some kind.
我猜你们也一定不知道那些文件是什么
And I don't suppose you know what was in those papers
也不知道马多克斯为什么出现在这儿
and why Maddox was here.
就像我刚才说的  我们只是路过
Like I said, we were just walking by.
我们差一点就知道真相了
We were so close.
那份文件本来可以告诉我们谁是幕后黑手
That file would've told us who's at the center of this
谁杀了我母亲
and who killed my mom.
至少马多克斯不会再追杀你了
Well, at least Maddox won't be coming after you.
他们还会派别人来杀我的
They'll just send somebody else.
除非幕后黑手
Unless whoever's behind all this
不知道文件已经被毁掉了
doesn't know the file's been destroyed.
或许他以为文件还好好的
Maybe he thinks it's still in play.
我觉得不太可能  你说呢
I wouldn't bet on that. Would you?
你能把枪收起来了吗
You want to put that thing away?
除非你不当叛徒了
Well, if it isn't Judas.
行  好的  哥们儿
Yeah, okay, pal.
你能别揪着那事不放了吗
You want to give it a break?
伙计们  别闹了
Guys, come on.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
给你们带来了这些东西
I came to bring you this.
保险柜里的文件
Paper from the safe?
我们现在要找些什么
Now what are we looking for?
名字  地址  日期
Names, places, dates--
任何能告诉我们那些文件里写了些什么的线索
anything that tells us what was in these files
以及为什么有人不惜一切地要隐藏它
and why someone is so desperate to keep it hidden.
忙活了五个小时了
Five hours,
我就只拼出扑克牌大小的一块来
and all I got is something the size of a playing card.
而且上面什么也没有
and not only that, it's blank.
我拼出一块写着"期末余额"
Yeah, well, I got "Ending balance" Here.
我觉得好像是张银行结单
I think it's some kind of bank statement.
不仅仅是张银行结单
Not just a bank statement.
这是一张现金汇票的一部分
This is part of a money order made out to cash.
可能是一笔黑钱
That could be a payoff.
收款人很有可能就是我们要找的人
And whoever it went to is probably our guy.
这就讲得通了
Well, that would make sense.
是吗  怎么讲
Yeah? In what way?
所有的这一切都起源于
Well, all of this started
蒙哥马利和他的警察兄弟们
when Montgomery and his cop buddies
开始绑架犯罪团伙成员并索要赎金
started kidnapping mobsters for ransom money.
我们知道有人发现了这个情况
And we know that someone found out
并想要从中抽成
and demanded a cut of that money.
无论那个人是谁
And whoever that is,
他都不想让文件里的内容泄漏出去
there's something in this file he does not want to get out.
这  这张上面有个数字
Whoa, this-- this has numbers on it.
还是打印的
And it's machine printed.
是个8位数字串  所以不可能是电话号码
It's an 8-digit string, so it's not a phone number.
等一下  那个是
Wait a minute. Oh, that's the--
这是那张汇票的反面
this is the back of that money order.
这些数字
And these digits,
0-8-6-7-2-2-4-1
0-8-6-7-2-2-4-1,
这是存款的账户
That's the account it was deposited in.
如果我们能查出这个账户是谁的
If we figure out whose account that is,
就能找到一个嫌疑人的名字
that should give us a name.
我想我知道一个办法
And I think I know a way.
还记得当时我们调查脏弹那个案子时
Uh, do you remember when we were checking
检查过一些银行账户吗
banking accounts for the dirty bomb investigation?
我们利用的是联邦银行数据库
We used the federal banking database.
我还记得数据库的密码
And I still remember the password.
我不确定能不能查到那么久以前的账户了
I'm not sure they even track accounts going back this far.
那个账户的主人
Whoever owns that account
就是杀我母亲的凶手
is the person that killed my mom.
查吧
Run it.
这个账户19年前就关闭了
The account was closed 19 years ago.
户主的名字是威廉·布莱肯
It belonged to a guy named William H. Bracken.
你是说威廉·布莱肯议员吧
You mean Senator William Bracken?
根据他竞选网站上的个人简历
According to the bio on his campaign web site,
布莱肯参议员曾在1988-1992年
Senator Bracken was assistant district attorney
担任纽约地区助理检察官
for New York from '88 till '92.
凯特
Kate?
我没事  卡塞尔
I'm fine, Castle.
布莱肯的时间线吻合
Bracken's timeline fits.
当时蒙哥马利正在绑架犯罪团伙成员
That's when Montgomery was kidnapping gangsters.
布莱肯一定是通过小道消息
Bracken must have heard about what they were doing
听说了他们的勾当
through the grapevine.
然后他意识到他无法提起公诉
And then he realized that he couldn't charge mobsters
因为黑帮成员不会出庭作证
because they wouldn't testify
那样那些警察就会逍遥法外
and then the cops would walk.
所以他索性参与其中
So instead he decided to get in on the action.
如果他们从罪犯那里收取赎金
If they were collecting ransom from mob guys,
他想分一杯羹  以现金汇票的形式抽成
He wanted a taste in the form of cash money orders.
对  不过随着他光辉的政坛生涯
Right, but as his political star rose
由国会议员一跃而升至参议员
from congressman to senator,
他意识到
he realized...
他必须确保这则丑闻永不见天日
He had to make sure the scandal never came to light.
接着就有人为此丧命
So then people started dying.
-这就解释了  -我是莱恩
- This would explain... - Ryan.
他现在为什么咬着你不放
Why he's coming after you right now.
有传言  说布莱肯被举荐竞选总统
Word is, Bracken's being groomed to run for president.
他想清理黑历史  你就是下一个
He's trying to clean house, and you're next.
我们得扳倒他
We need to take him down.
怎么扳  我们手头只握有一些数字
How? All we have are a bunch of numbers
除了对我们  对其他任何人都毫无意义
that are meaningless to anyone but us.
我们根本没有指控他的铁证
We have absolutely no hard evidence against him.
或许我手中有条次一些的线索
Uh, I may have the next best thing.
我刚收到消息
I just got word
迈克尔·史密斯刚做完手术
that Michael Smith is out of surgery,
而且醒来了
And he's awake.
史密斯就是关键
Smith is the key.
他能把全部线索与布莱肯联系上
He can connect all this to Bracken.
那好  我和卡塞尔去找他谈谈
Okay, Castle and I are gonna go talk to him.
你们试着能不能找出
You guys see if you can find the link
马多克斯和布莱肯之间的联系
between Maddox and Bracken.
莱恩打电话说了
Ryan call you?
是的  说了
Yeah, yeah.
你们还活着
You're alive.
彼此彼此
Join the club.
那一部分文件呢
What about the other file?
马多克斯打开了保险箱
Maddox opened the safe.
拼凑之下  我们发现布莱肯收了黑钱
We put enough of it together to know that Bracken took dirty money.
关门
Close the door.
讽刺的是  他用那笔黑钱赞助了
The irony is, he used that money to finance
自己的头一次国会竞选
his first congressional campaign.
我们需要证据证明这一点
We need proof of that,
连同他所犯下的一切罪恶
along with anything else that he did.
没有证据
There is no proof.
不是还有你吗  你可以作证
Well, there's you. You can testify.
那是不可能的
That will never happen.
罗伊·蒙哥马利帮过我一个忙
You see, Roy Montgomery once did me a favor.
我才会藏着那份文件  才会保护你
So I kept that file and I protected you
我付出了很大的代价
At great personal cost
因为我欠罗伊的
because I owed Roy.
可我不欠你的
But I don't owe you.
你就打算这么让他
So you're just gonna let him
逃脱谋杀罪的制裁吗
G-get away with murder?
你不明白  探长
You don't understand, detective.
他有保护伞  动不得
He's protected, untouchable.
你的结局只会是死路一条
You're just gonna end up dead,
我也难逃一死
And so am I.
现在看来
Now as it is,
我最好的办法  就是
My best bet is to just...
销声匿迹
Disappear.
我也这么建议你
I suggest you do the same.
你清楚自己知道得太多了
You know that you know too much,
就和罗伊还有我母亲一样
just like Roy and my mom did.
他们找到了你一次  就还能再找到你
They found you once. They will find you again.
你唯一的办法就是跟我合作
And your only bet is to work with me.
我累了
I'm tired.
你们该走了
You need to go.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
对  你们一查到任何线索就通知我
Yeah, you just let me know if you figure anything out.
是莱恩的电话
All right. That was Ryan.
他说他们
He said they found
查不到马多克斯和布莱肯之间确凿的联系
no concrete connection between Maddox and Bracken.
是啊  我们找不到的
Yeah, and we won't find one.
他太小心了
He's too careful.
史密斯就是关联
Smith is the connection.
没错  但他不愿意合作  卡塞尔
Yeah, but he won't cooperate, Castle.
他刚刚已经说得很明确了
He's already made that clear.
那是他唯一的活路了
This is his only play.
他那么聪明应该知道这一点
He's smart enough to know that.
他只是需要一点鼓动
He just needs a little bit of encouragement.
好吧
Okay.
等等  你怎么不守着史密斯
Hey. Wait. Why aren't you with Smith?
调度室打来让我离开的
Dispatch called and told me to stand down.
慢着  出什么事了
Wait. Wait. What happened?
似乎是心脏病发作  我们已经尽力了
Looks like a heart attack. We did everything we could.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我很骄傲地向大家引荐
I am proud to introduce to you
美国副总统
The Vice President of the United States--
约翰·罗素先生
Mr. John Russell.
谢谢  布莱肯参议员
Thank you, senator Bracken.
我终于查到了那个人
I finally figured out who he is--
那个杀害了我母亲的人
The guy that killed my mom--
可我现在却束手无策
And there's nothing I can do about it.
莱恩跟你通话了吗
Did Ryan talk to you?
他查过了史密斯病房周围的
Did he check those security cameras
那些监控录像了吗
around Smith's room?
查了
Yes.
结果呢
And?
摄像头失都灵了
The cameras were disabled.
好吧  他们要冲着我来了
Okay. So they're coming for me.
莱恩派了两队人守在外面
Ryan's got two teams stationed outside.
那明天怎么办
And what about tomorrow
后天又该怎么办
and the day after that?
让我带你走吧  凯特
Let me take you someplace, Kate,
去个你会安全的地方
Someplace you'll be safe.
我再无宁日了
I'll never be safe.
什么叫她不在这里
What do you mean, she's not here?
就是她人不在这里
I mean, she's not here
电话也不接
and she's not answering her cell.
你不是派人盯着她了吗
I thought you had a detail on her.
我有啊  现在还盯着呢
I did. I do.
如果她离开了这栋楼
If she would've left this building,
他们会注意到她的
They would've seen her.
除非她不想被发现
Not if she didn't want them to.
布莱肯议员现在在哪里
Where is Senator Bracken right now?
兄弟  你该不会认为她...
Oh, man, you don't think that she--
是的  我是莱恩警探
Yeah, it's Detective Kevin Ryan,
警员编号42344
Badge number 4-2-3-4-4.
请帮我查一下布莱肯议员的具体位置
Can I get a 20 on Senator Bracken?
他在维马克酒店主持一场募捐会
He's hosting a fund-raiser at the Widmark Hotel.
问问有没有人查问过他的行踪
Ask if anyone else has called to check on him.
还有其他人问过他的行踪吗
Did anyone call to check on him?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
贝克特一小时前也给他们打过电话
Beckett phoned 'em an hour ago.
她会直接把布莱肯议员干掉的
She's gonna kill Senator Bracken.
你好  黑斯廷
Hey, Hastings.
你好  贝克特探长
Hey, Detective Beckett.
她们把你也派来做安保工作啦
They got you on security detail, too?
是的  我有点事要和里面的人谈谈
Yeah. You know, I need to speak with someone.
你能直接让我过去吗
You think I could jump this line?
是你  当然没问题
For you? Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
你们支持我的选举吗
Are you with me on that?
我该亲吻宝宝才对吧
I'm supposed to be kissing babies.
你根本是在浪费时间  探长
You're wasting your time, Detective.
你完全不知道自己面对的对手是谁
You have no idea what you're up against.
你已把恶魔唤醒
You woke the dragon.
这事要比你想象的严重得多
And this is so much bigger than you realize.
一人做事一人当  凯特
This is my spot, Kate.
这就是我的选择
This is where I stand.
你们支持我的选举吗
Are you with me on that?
-支持  -感谢大家
- Yeah! - Thank you.
抱歉  我接个电话  马上回来
Please excuse me just--just-- just for one minute.
抱歉...
Please. Just...
你好
Hello.
我是凯特·贝克特
This is Kate Beckett.
从你的表情看  你对这名字不陌生
I can see you know the name.
是的  我正看着你呢
That's right. I'm watching.
我不知道你要干什么
I don't know what this is about,
但我对玩游戏不感兴趣
But I am not interested in playing games.
那你最好培养一下兴趣
Well, you better get interested.
我手上有能摧毁你政治生涯的信息
I have information that will destroy your career
你若不照我说的做  我便会用它毁掉你
and I will use it unless you do exactly as I say.
我们得跟布莱肯议员谈谈
We need to talk to Senator Bracken.
他正在与一位捐赠人会谈
He's in meeting with a donor.
什么捐赠人  他在哪
What donor? Where is he?
他没有说
He didn't say.
你要给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
盖茨吗
Gates?
把电话放回去  不然我就扭断你的手臂
Put that phone away or I'm gonna break your friggin' arm.
哈维尔  我们不能眼睁睁地看她去送死
Javi, we can't let her throw her life away.
我们还不确定她是否真要那么做
We don't know she's doing that.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
是你说她会直接把那家伙干掉的
You're the one who said she was gonna kill the guy.
好吧  我知道  对  但是...
Okay, I know. Okay, yes, that's right, but...
但她还没动手  对吧
But she hasn't done that yet, right?
如果你打了那通电话
Look, you make that call,
就给她贴上了杀手的标签
you're labeling her an assassin.
以后想撕也撕不下来了
That's a bell you can't unring.
所以  暂时先别告诉盖茨吧
So let's not make that call, not yet.
好吧
All right.
就站那儿够了
That's far enough.
你想要什么  贝克特女士
What do you want, Ms. Beckett?
真相
The truth.
永远别向政客索要真相
Never expect that from a politician.
再说  你手上如果真有什么信息
Besides, if you really had information,
你不该早就了解真相了吗
Wouldn't you already know the truth?
罗伊·蒙哥马利  麦卡利斯特
Roy Montgomery, McCallister,
约翰·拉格兰和我母亲
John Raglan, my mother--
每一个被你杀害的人
Everyone that you've ever had killed,
我要你承认你的罪行
I want you to admit to it.
你母亲的死是个悲剧
Your mother's death was a tragedy...
我对此深表哀悼
and I am deeply sorry for your loss.
但我不能满足你的要求
But I can't give you what you want.
我14岁的时候
When I was 14,
与邻家的小男孩成了好朋友
I got to be friends with this boy in the neighborhood--
他叫拉玛·德克斯  是个很可爱的孩子
Lamar Dokes. Sweet kid.
放学后我常常帮他复习功课
I used to help him with his homework after school.
有一天  他没去上学
Well, one day, he doesn't come to school.
所以我到他家去看他
So I went by his apartment
他家的门是敞开的
And the door was open.
我进去了
I walked in
然后
And...
我发现拉玛躺在他的床上  死了
I found Lamar lying on his mattress... dead,
他的小妹妹也一样
His little sister the same way.
他母亲在卧室
His mother was in the bedroom.
上吊死了
She had hanged herself.
她留下一张纸条  说她丢了工作
Now she left a note. She'd lost her job.
将被驱逐出境
She was being evicted.
当时我就想  一个女人
And I thought, how could a woman
怎能如此万念俱灰  失去一切希望
be so desperate, so without hope,
以至于她竟把药片碾碎
that she could crush up pills,
融进热可可里
put them in hot chocolate,
喂给自己的孩子喝
and give them to her kids?
就在那一刻...
And that was the moment...
那一刻我意识到
The moment I knew
我要帮助人们过上更美好的生活
I wanted to help make people's lives better.
我也做到了
And I have.
我加强了社会保障制度
I strengthened the safety net
保护像拉玛一样的孩子
to protect kids like Lamar.
我在那些社区创造了就业机会
I created jobs in those neighborhoods.
我做了许多好事
I've done great things...
正如你也做了许多好事
Just as you've done great things.
你以为你在和谁说话
Who do you think you're talking to?
你有什么资格在我面前为自己辩解
How can you justify yourself to me?
我母亲因为你  在小巷中被捅死
My mother was stabbed in an alley because of you.
她在垃圾堆中  孤零零地流血至死
She bled to death alone in a pile of garbage!
所以省省你那竞选的演讲词
So save me your campaign speeches
少说些狗屁美好的事吧
about the great things.
你似乎有点妄想症  你知道吧
You sound a bit delusional, you know?
话说回来  你是谁
But then again, who are you?
你是一个丢脸的警察
You're a disgraced cop,
深陷自己母亲的谋杀案中
obsessed with her mother's murder.
而我是谁
And who am I?
我是一个高尚的关心底层群众利益的人
I'm a decent man looking out for the little guy.
公众眼中的我就是那样的
That's who the public sees.
每次他们选我的时候
And every time they elect me,
我都心怀卑谦
I'm humbled.
我会更加努力地去实现这个理想
I strive harder to live up to that ideal.
我想要成为那样的人
I want to be that man.
我也绝不会让你或是其他任何人
And I won't let you or anyone else
挡我的路
get in my way.
我觉得你现在没资格威胁我  参议员
I don't think you're in a position to threaten, senator.
瞧  所以说你不明白
See, here's what you don't understand--
这不取决于谁手中有枪
It's not who has the gun,
而取决于谁握有掌控权
it's who has the power.
你真的觉得是你吗
Do you really think that's you?
我拿到文件了
I have the file.
史密斯还有一份复件
Smith had another copy.
08672241
0-8-6-7-2-2-4-1.
那是你当年
That's the number of the bank account
存入汇款的银行账户
where you deposited the money orders.
所以你说的对
So you're right.
关键就在于谁握有掌控权
It is about who holds the power.
现在我可以公开文件  让你身败名裂
Now I could release that file and destroy you,
但是这样做对我又有什么意义呢
but what would that mean for my life expectancy?
所以现在这样
So here's how it is--
你和史密斯的交易
The deal that you had with Smith,
改成我们之间的交易
that's our deal now.
如果我或者任何我在乎的人  发生任何不测
And if anything happens to me or anyone that I care about,
文件就会公之于众
that file goes public.
清楚了吗
Am I clear?
回答是或者否
That's a yes-or-no question.
是
Yes.
还有一件事
And one more thing.
不管你觉得我是谁
Whoever it is you think I am,
不管你觉得自己了解我什么
whatever it is you think you know about me,
你根本想不到我能干出什么事
you have no idea what I'm capable of
或者做到什么地步
or how far I will go.
我担惊受怕够了
I am done being afraid.
现在  轮到你了
It's your turn now.
那会留下一道丑陋的伤疤
That's gonna leave a nasty scar.
每次你一看到它
Every time you see it,
就想想我
think of me.
凯特  告诉我你没...
Kate, tell me you didn't...
我们达成了共识
We reached an understanding.
你妈的案子怎么办
What about your mom?
我会为她寻得正义
I'll get justice for her.
只是不是今天
Just not today.
在那之前
Until then,
我要为其他人伸张正义
I'll get it for others.
你的辞职已经被批准了
Your resignation has been accepted.
已成定局
The matter is settled.
长官   在本区我的破案率最高
Sir, I have the top case-closure rate in the precinct.
现在那个开枪杀我的人已经死了
And now that the man that shot me is dead,
那个特案不会再是问题了
that particular case will no longer be an issue.
是吗
Really?
似乎那个特案时不时就会闹出些事
Because it seems to be the gift that keeps on giving.
我听说我们之前在医院
I'm told we put a Michael Smith
监控着一个叫迈克尔·史密斯的人
under guard at the hospital.
他和本案有什么关系
What was his role in this?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
你在掩护某人  我知道是谁
You're covering for someone, and I know who it is.
但是我不打算深究过去的事情
But I don't intend to dig up the past
玷污罗伊·蒙哥马利的名誉
and tarnish Roy Montgomery's reputation.
实际上  我
The fact is, I...
我敬佩你的忠诚
I admire your loyalty.
我希望有一天你也能对我如此
I hope you feel that for me someday.
那是否意味着我明天可以来上班了呢
Does that mean I can show up for duty tomorrow?
不行  她说不行是什么意思
No? What does she mean, no?
我得服满停职期
Well, I have to serve out my suspension,
埃斯波西托也是
same as Esposito.
这期间你打算干什么呢
What are you gonna do in the meantime?
我确定我会想到事情做的
Oh, I'm pretty sure I'll think of something.